# 哈喽大家好
Hi guys!
# 前段时间我兄弟送我的竹鼠
The bamboo rats sent by my bro
# 让漆二娃喂 喂了几天跑掉了一只
I asked Qi Erwa to feed them. A few days later one of them ran away
# 然后前两天她又把它抓回来了
She caught it back a few days ago
# 现在我们准备把它做成腊竹鼠
Now we decide to turn it into cured meat
# 再加几只鸭子
With a few ducks
# 一起做
Cured together
# 鸭子差不多也喂了半年了
The ducks are about 6 months old
# 我们现在去逮鸭子
Now we're going to fetch the ducks
# 先杀竹鼠
Prepare the bamboo rats first
# 要得
Sure
# 这样子 漆二娃你先烧一锅水
Let's do this way. Qi Erwa, you boil a wok of water
# 好
Okay
# 拿那个铁锅烧
With that iron wok
# 嗯 要得
Um, will do
# 还想跑
Trying to flee?
# 这两个竹鼠装在一起了还要打架
These two rats are still fighting each other even in the same cage
# 还没弄干净吗
Not cleaned yet?
# 快当了
Nearly
# 我都把两个竹鼠解决归一了
I'm already done with these two rats
# 耶 你的级别是要搞得快点
Yeah, your rank should be matched with a greater speed
# 没有多少毛了
Not much hair is left
# 你先弄到嘛我去弄盐巴
You sort these out. I'm going to prepare the salt
# 好好好 去拿盐巴拿起来嘛
Cool cool, go get the salts
# 那两只也一起开了嘛
What about you preparing these two as well
# 要得嘛
Of course
# 那这样我就去炒盐巴去了哦
I go and toast the salt then
# 要得
Cool
# 我烧小点哦
I will lower the fire
# 其实我们四川人做腌腊的东西都喜欢把这个盐炒成熟盐
In fact, we Sichuan people prefer to use cooked salt for meat-curing
# 放点香料花椒下去炒
Toast with some spices and pepper
# 这样做出来更香一点
which can enhance the aroma
# 放几颗八角
A few star anises
# 再放一点香叶
Some bay leaves
# 再加点花椒
Also some Sichuan peppercorns
# 这个花椒好香
The pepper smells so good!
# 来你来炒一会儿 漆二娃
Come on Qi Erwa, you toast it for a while
# 今天我们杀了4个鸭子还有2个竹鼠
Today we have 4 ducks and 2 bamboo rats
# 提前把它腌好
Season them in advance
# 把它挂在柴房
And hang them in our Chai Fang (lit. kitchen stored with firewood)
# 我们是不是叫柴房哦
Do we call it Chai Fang?
# 灶门千
"Zao Men Qian"
# 就是放在柴房一直放在那里熏
So it's like, putting in Chai Fang and keep smoking them
# 放在烟囱旁边熏
Beside the fire and smoke
# 来嘛四伯爷 把这个提起来
Uncle, help me lift them up
# 提起来我把水拿来倒了
I'm gonna dump the water
# 好不好拿
y'alright?
# 还有2个竹鼠
and 2 bamboo rats
# 开玩笑火云邪神这点劳力都没得啊
ya kiddin' me? Me "The Beast" cannot live without 'dis strength (from the movie "Kung Fu Hustle")
# 跟他们说的样
given that they call me
# 放点酒给它摸哈
rub it wi' some cookin' wine
# 才看斗舒服
looks fab
# 下面的个还没有倒上
this one underneath is yet to cover
# 好
Done
# 嘿 这个酒倒上去好香哦
Smells so good with the wine
# 肯定撒
Definitely
# 这个盐巴还没怎么冷不过还用得
The salt hasn't cooled down, but we can still use it
# 香料炒的 花椒
cooked with spices, Sichuan peppercorns
# 好
season it a bit more salted
# 腌咸一点哦
I'm ok with more salt
# 咸点可以
Not a big problem. We can rinse for a few more times when we cook them
# 反正不关事 到时候做的时候再把它多煮几次再洗哈
Seems that you like this name "The Beast"
# 这下子你还是比较喜欢火云邪神这个名字哦
Aiya, like they said
# 哎呀 跟他们说的那样
Fans all call me with that name
# 铺都铺了牌了
What for?
# 有啥子啊
I think you didn't know what this name meant initially
# 刚开始你是不是不晓得这是什么名字
Duuno, can't figure it out
# 不晓得 不晓得请不到过张
Great
# 好
Yeah, almost there
# 嗯 差不多了
We used a bit more salt
# 我们这个做得咸了一点点
The reason is that
# 为什么做咸一点呢
Probably these
# 可能这几个到时候保存得更久一点
Can hold for a longer time
# 盐放的越多就保存得越久
More salt can keep the cured food for longer
# 咸一点保质期就久一点撒
More salty, longer the quality period becomes!
# 嗯
Um
# 诶哟
Whoops
# 注意点哈
take care!
# 诶哟 花到手了
My hand gets cut
# 漆二娃你来弄
Qi Erwa, come and help with this
# 好
Sure!
# 拿酒酒酒
Get the wine!
# 小心点四伯爷这个也有刺（尖骨头）
Take care uncle this one has splinters too
# 我清得到
I can handle that
# 刚才弄到手了
I just hurt my hand
# 花到这个竹鼠
by this, bamboo rat's bone splinter
# 我都花到手了所以让他们弄
My hand's hurt so I have to let them help me
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里结束啦
Okay. That's all for today's video
# 拜拜
Bye Bye
Bye bye
# 我去弄创可贴包一下
I need to grab a band-aid
# 好
Ok